Guide to the Pierce County Central Labor Council Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Pierce County Central Labor Council records, 1890-1970; 2882-001; 30.83 cubic feet
  - PIERCE COUNTY CENTRAL LABOR COUNCIL, Records Subgroup 1
    - RESOLUTIONS, STATEMENTS, AND WRITINGS, 1900-1968; SERIES IX (Box-folder 26/6-26/22)
      - Resolutions of other organizations, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 26/15)
      - Resolutions of other organizations, Undated (Box-folder 26/16)
      - Statements of other organizations, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 26/17)
      - Statements of other organizations, 1931-1939 (Box-folder 26/18)
      - Statements of other organizations, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 26/19)
      - Statements of other organizations, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 26/20)
      - Statements of other organizations, Undated (Box-folder 26/21)
      - Petitions, 1922-1933, Undated (Box-folder 26/22)
    - ADMINISTRATIVE AND GOVERNANCE RECORDS, 1914-1966; SERIES X (Box-folder 26/23-26/26)
      - Inventories, 1920-1924 (Box-folder 26/23)
      - Ballots, tallies, 1922-1966 (Box-folder 26/24)
      - Lists, 1915-1933, Undated (Box-folder 26/25)
      - Forms, questionnaires, 1914-1962 (Box-folder 26/26)
    - RECORDS OF POLITICAL ACTIVITIES, 1917-1937; SERIES XI (Box-folder 26/27-27/1)
      - Legislation (Sate and National), 1917-1937, Undated (Box-folder 26/27)
      - Election precinct file, Undated (Box-folder 27/1)
    - CONFERENCE AND CONVENTION RECORDS, 1901-1968; SERIES XII (Box-folder 28/1-28/11)
      - Proceedings of Labor Congress of the State of Washington, 1901 (Box-folder 28/1)
      - Joint Conference of the State Federation of Labor and Organized Labor of Tacoma, 1919 (Box-folder 28/2)
      - United Labor Political Conference of Pierce County, Washington, Undated (Box-folder 28/3)
      - Governor's Industrial Safety Conference, 1968 (Box-folder 28/4)
      - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1929-1937 (Box-folder 28/5)
      - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1952 (Box-folder 28/6)
      - Washington State Labor Council, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 28/7)
      - Washington State Labor Council, 1966 (Box-folder 28/8)
      - AFL, AFL-CIO, 1922-1967 (Box-folder 28/9)
      - National Women's Trade Union League of America, 1922 (Box-folder 28/10)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades Convention, 1918 (Box-folder 28/11)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS, 1949-1952; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 28/12-28/13)
      - Photographic prints, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 28/12)
      - Photoengraving, zinc plate with 6 portraits, Undated (Box-folder 28/13)
    - NEWS RELEASES AND PRESS CLIPPINGS, 1917-1967; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 28/14-28/21, 55/1)
      - News releases, 1917-1967 (Box-folder 28/14)
      - News clippings, 1919 (Box-folder 28/15)
      - News clippings, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 28/16)
      - Clippings re Marinoff Northwest Brewing Company dispute, 1935 (Box-folder 28/17)
      - Clipping and circulars re Initiative 130, 1938 (Box-folder 28/18)
      - News clippings, 1944-1956 (Box-folder 28/19)
      - Clippings re new Tacoma City Charter proposal (part 1 of 2), 1955-1956 (Box-folder 28/20)
      - Clippings re new Tacoma City Charter proposal (part 2 of 2), 1955-1956 (Box-folder 28/21)
      - Scrapbook including press clippings, leaflets and circulars, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 64)
      - Clipping scrapbook including Tacoma City Charter news, 1955 (Box-folder 55/1)
      - Clipping scrapbook including Tacoma City Charter news, 1956-1956 (Box-folder 65)
    - PUBLICATIONS, EPHEMERA, AND MEMORABILIA, 1912-1970; SERIES XV (Box-folder 28/22-29/11, 55/2)
      - Newsletters, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 28/22)
      - Monthly Survey of Business, 1929-1935 (Box-folder 29/1)
      - Labor's Monthly Survey, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 29/2)
      - Labor's Monthly Survey, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 29/3)
      - AFL Legal Information Bureau bulletins, 1924 (Box-folder 29/4)
      - Centralia Publicity Committee bulletins, 1933 (Box-folder 29/5)
      - Chest for LIberation of Workers of Europe bulletins, 1935 (Box-folder 29/6)
      - Newsletters and bulletins of others, 1920-1966 (Box-folder 29/7)
      - Publications of others, 1917-1945 (Box-folder 29/8)
      - Ephemera, 1918-1964 (Box-folder 29/9)
      - Ephemera, 1920-1965 (Box-folder 29/10)
      - Memorabilia, 1949-1970 (Box-folder 29/11)
      - Charters and certificates of affiliation, 1912-1930 (Box-folder 55/2)
      - Certificate of affiliation, scrapbook concerning lumber and sawmill workers organizing, 1935 (Folder:oversize Oversize Folder)
    - SUBJECT FILES, 1909-1968; SERIES XVI (Box-folder 30/1-31/64)
      - Signers for Freeholders election (part 1 of 2), Undated (Box-folder 30/1)
      - Signers for Freeholders election (part 2 of 2), Undated (Box-folder 30/2)
      - General strike vote reports from affiliates, 1919 (Box-folder 30/3)
      - Record of votes cast on Mooney general strike ballot, 1919 (Box-folder 30/4)
      - Initiative 130, 1938 (Box-folder 30/5)
      - Lucas case, Undated (Box-folder 30/6)
      - Harry McIlvaigh testimonial dinner, 1963 (Box-folder 30/7)
      - Merger of former Tacoma Central Labor Council, AFL, and former Pierce County Industrial Union Council, CIO, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 30/8)
      - Seven cent streetcar fare proposition, 1918 (Box-folder 30/9)
      - Private John J. Sinchak, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 30/10)
      - Smelter case, 1914 (Box-folder 30/11)
      - Tacoma. Metropolitan Park Board financial reports, 1918-1923 (Box-folder 30/12)
      - Tacoma Rochdale Union (part 1 of 2), 1919 (Box-folder 30/13)
      - Tacoma Rochdale Union (part 2 of 2), 1919 (Box-folder 30/14)
      - Pierce County Triple Alliance, 1920 (Box-folder 30/15)
      - Union label / we don't patronize, 1917-1961 (Box-folder 30/16)
      - Unions contributing to throw-away "we don't patronize" list, 1964 (Box-folder 30/17)
      - US War Department Spruce Production Division, 1918 (Box-folder 30/18)
      - Washington. Western State Hospital, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 31/1)
      - Journeyman Barbers International Union Local 158, 1918 (Box-folder 31/2)
      - Bill Posters and Billers Union Local 49, 1934 (Box-folder 31/3)
      - International Brotherhood of Blacksmiths, Drop Forgers and Helpers, Undated (Box-folder 31/4)
      - International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders and Helpers of America. Pacific Coast District Council, 1918 (Box-folder 31/5)
      - Building Service Employees Union Local 38, 1938-1950 (Box-folder 31/6)
      - Building Trades Council, Tacoma, 1922 (Box-folder 31/7)
      - Butter, Egg and Produce Workers, 1918 (Box-folder 31/8)
      - United Brotherhood of Carpenter and Joiners of America, 1918-1935 (Box-folder 31/9)
      - Cereal and Flour Mill Workers Industrial Council of Tacoma, Undated (Box-folder 31/10)
      - City Employees Joint Council, Tacoma, Undated (Box-folder 31/11)
      - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America Local 68, 1918-1936 (Box-folder 31/12)
      - Coppersmiths Local No. 631 bylaws, Undated (Box-folder 31/13)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 76, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 31/14)
      - International Union of Steam and Operating Engineers Local 606, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 31/15)
      - City Firefighters Union No. 31, 1919, Undated (Box-folder 31/16)
      - Fishermens Co-operative Association, 1936 (Box-folder 31/17)
      - Furniture Workers (Box-folder 31/18)
      - United Garment Workers of America Local 201, 1914 (Box-folder 31/19)
      - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' International Alliance, 1937 (Box-folder 31/20)
      - International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers Local 581, Undated (Box-folder 31/21)
      - Iron Workers and Pile Drivers Northwest District Council, Undated (Box-folder 31/22)
      - Hod Carriers and Building Laborers of America Local 252, 1919 (Box-folder 31/23)
      - Labor Forward, 1915 (Box-folder 31/24)
      - International Union of Laundry Workers Local 42, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 31/25)
      - International Longshoremen's Association Local 38-A, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 31/26)
      - International Longshoremen's Association Local 38-3, 1918-1937 (Box-folder 31/27)
      - International Longshoremen's Association Local 38-43, 1918 (Box-folder 31/28)
      - ILA Defense Committee, 1934 (Box-folder 31/29)
      - Lumber and Sawmill Workers Puget Sound District Council, 1936, Undated (Box-folder 31/30)
      - International Association of Machinists Local 297, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 31/31)
      - Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America Locals 553, 554, 1935-1938, Undated (Box-folder 31/32)
      - Millwrights Local 1923, 1918 (Box-folder 31/33)
      - International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Local 27, 1918, Undated (Box-folder 31/34)
      - Municipal Employees Union Local 16151, 1919 (Box-folder 31/35)
      - American Federation of Musicians Local 117, Undated (Box-folder 31/36)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council, 1918-1959 (Box-folder 31/37)
      - Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America Local 64, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 31/38)
      - Sign, Pictorial Painters and Displaymen's Local 403, 1919-1963 (Box-folder 31/39)
      - Plasterers' and Cement Masons' International Association Local 71, 1919-1968 (Box-folder 31/40)
      - Private Soldiers and Sailors' Legion, 1920 (Box-folder 31/41)
      - Retail Clerks International Protective Association Local 231 (Drug Clerks), 1936, Undated-1936 (Box-folder 31/42)
      - Service Station Attendants, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 31/43)
      - Shade and Drapery Workers, Carpet and Linoleum Mechanics International Union, 1936 (Box-folder 31/44)
      - Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers Northwest District Council, 1919, Undated-1919 (Box-folder 31/45)
      - Shipwrights, 1918 (Box-folder 31/46)
      - Shipyard Laborers of Pacific Northwest Local 15598, Undated (Box-folder 31/47)
      - Boot and Shoe Workers' Union Local 173, 1946 (Box-folder 31/48)
      - Soldiers' and Sailors' Council of Tacoma, c. 1919 (Box-folder 31/49)
      - Soldiers', Sailors' and Workmen's Council, Women's Branch, 1919 (Box-folder 31/50)
      - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees Local 793, Undated (Box-folder 31/51)
      - Stenographers, Typists, Bookkeepers and Assistants' Union Local 20360, 1937 (Box-folder 31/52)
      - Amalgamated Association of Street and Electric Railway Employees of America Division 758, 1918 (Box-folder 31/53)
      - American Federation of Teachers Local 458, Undated (Box-folder 31/54)
      - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Joint Council, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 31/55)
      - International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 313, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 31/56)
      - Theatrical Crafts Federation of Oregon, Washington and British Columbia, 1922 (Box-folder 31/57)
      - International Union of Timber Workers Local 70, 1918 (Box-folder 31/58)
      - International Typographical Union Local 170, 1909-1920 (Box-folder 31/59)
      - Upholsterers' International Union of North America Local 40, 1935 (Box-folder 31/60)
      - Waterfront Workers Federation of Tacoma, 1919 (Box-folder 31/61)
      - Washington State Labor Council, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 31/62)
      - International Woodworkers of America Local 3-9, c. 1964 (Box-folder 31/63)
      - Workers, Soldiers and Sailors Council, 1919 (Box-folder 31/64)
    - Pierce County Committee on Political Education, 1958-1972; Records Subgroup 2 (Box-folder 31/65-32/17)
      - CORRESPONDENCE, 1958-1972; SERIES I (Box-folder 31/65-32/4)
        - General correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 31/65)
        - General correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 31/66)
        - General correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 31/67)
        - General correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 32/1)
        - General correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 32/2)
        - General correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 32/3)
        - Interoffice correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 32/4)
      - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1958-1972; SERIES II (Box-folder 32/5-32/9)
        - Financial records, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 32/5)
        - Minutes, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 32/6)
        - Reports, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 32/7)
        - Conferences and conventions, 1961 (Box-folder 32/8)
        - Lists, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 32/9)
      - SUBJECT FILES, 1963-1971; SERIES III (Box-folder 32/10-323/17)
        - Campaign materials, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 32/10)
        - Press clippings, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 32/11)
        - Committee to Promote Labor's Political Program, 1964 (Box-folder 32/12)
        - United Labor Lobby, 1963 (Box-folder 32/13)
        - Voter registration drive correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 32/14)
        - Voter registration drive lists, 1966 (Box-folder 32/15)
        - Voter registration drive financial records, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 32/16)
        - Voter registration drive campaign materials, 1964 (Box-folder 32/17)
      - Central Labor Council Labor Day Committee, 1914-1937; Records Subgroup 3 (Box-folder 32/18-33/4)
        - General correspondence, 1914-1935 (Box-folder 32/18)
        - Minutes, 1924-1937 (Box-folder 32/19)
        - Financial records, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 33/1)
        - Reports, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 33/2)
        - Picnic programs, Undated (Box-folder 33/3)
        - Miscellaneous, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Labor Temple Corporation, 1918-1959; Records Subgroup 4 (Box-folder 33/5-34/8)
    - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1918-1941; SERIES I (Box-folder 33/5-33/9, 53/1, 56/1)
      - Articles of incorporation, 1941 (Box-folder 33/5)
      - Pierce County Labor Temple Corporation: minutes, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 33/6)
      - Pierce County Labor Temple Corporation: minutes, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 56/1)
      - Pierce County Labor Temple Corporation: minutes, 1941-1947 (Box-folder 53/1)
      - Labor Temple Committee: minutes, 1939 (Box-folder 33/7)
      - Labor Temple Corporation and CLC joint meetings: minutes, 1941 (Box-folder 33/8)
      - First annual report of Secretary, Pierce County Labor Temple Corporation, 1918 (Box-folder 33/9)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1913-1948; SERIES II (Box-folder 33/10-33/11)
      - General correspondence, 1913-1924 (Box-folder 33/10)
      - General correspondence, 1939-1948 (Box-folder 33/11)
    - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1918-1959; SERIES III (Box-folder 33/12-34/5, 53/2)
      - Ledger, 1918-1928 (Box-folder 33/12)
      - Ledger, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 33/13)
      - Cash book / journal, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 53/2)
      - Labor Temple Club profit and loss statements, 1942-1952 (Box-folder 33/14)
      - Trial balances, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 33/15)
      - Trial balances, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 33/16)
      - Trial balances, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 33/17)
      - Annual financial reports, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 33/18)
      - Income tax returns, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 34/1)
      - Income tax returns, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 34/2)
      - Income tax returns, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 34/3)
      - General financial and payroll, 1941-1959 (Box-folder 34/4)
      - Donations to Labor Temple fund, 1941 (Box-folder 34/5)
    - PROPERTY RECORDS, 1939-1941; SERIES IV (Box-folder 34/6-34/8)
      - Building purchase negotiations, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 34/6)
      - Statement on building purchase, 1941 (Box-folder 34/7)
      - Land contract, deed, agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 34/8)
  - Mother Robinson Committee, 1920; Records Subgroup 5 (Box-folder 34/9)
    - Reports, fundraising and expenditures, 1920 (Box-folder 34/9)
  - Labor Advocate Publishing Company, 1910-1968; Records Subgroup 6 (Box-folder 34/10-35/5)
    - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1918-1968; SERIES I (Box-folder 34/10-34/15)
      - Historical and by-laws, 1919-1968 (Box-folder 34/10)
      - Minutes, 1915-1923 (Box-folder 34/11)
      - Board of Control minutes, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 34/12)
      - Board of Control minutes, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 51/3)
      - Board of Control minutes, 1925-1945 (Box-folder 52/1)
      - Board of Control minutes, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 34/13)
      - Board of Control minutes, undated (Box-folder 34/14)
      - Labor Advocate Press Fund Committee minutes, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 34/15)
      - Correspondence, 1918 (Box-folder 34/16)
    - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1910-1966; SERIES I (Box-folder 34/16-35/5, 57/1-57/9)
      - Financial reports, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 34/17)
      - Journal, 1931-1942 (Box-folder 34/18)
      - General journal, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 57/1)
      - General journal, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 57/2)
      - General journal, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 57/3)
      - Cash journal, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 62/1)
      - Cash journal, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 62/2)
      - Cash journal, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 63/1)
      - Cash journal, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 63/2)
      - Cash journal, 1946 (Box-folder 57/4)
      - Cash journal, 1954 (Box-folder 57/5)
      - Sales journal, 1946 (Box-folder 57/6)
      - Sales journal, 1954 (Box-folder 57/7)
      - Monthly profit and loss statements, 1944-1959 (Box-folder 57/8)
      - Trial balances, 1946-1960 (Box-folder 57/9)
      - Ledger (part 1 of 3), 1935-1942 (Box-folder 35/1)
      - Ledger (part 2 of 3), 1935-1942 (Box-folder 35/2)
      - Ledger (part 3 of 3), 1935-1942 (Box-folder 35/3)
      - Ledger, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 35/4)
      - Ledger, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 35/5)
      - Ledger, 1947 (Box-folder 35/6)
      - Ledger, 1948 (Box-folder 35/7)
      - Ledger, 1949 (Box-folder 35/8)
      - Ledger, 1950 (Box-folder 35/9)
      - Ledger, 1951 (Box-folder 35/10)
      - Ledger, 1952 (Box-folder 35/11)
      - Ledger, 1953 (Box-folder 36/1)
      - Ledger, 1954 (Box-folder 36/2)
      - Ledger, 1955 (Box-folder 36/3)
      - Ledger, 1956 (Box-folder 36/4)
      - Ledger, 1957 (Box-folder 36/5)
      - Ledger, 1958 (Box-folder 36/6)
      - Ledger, 1959 (Box-folder 36/7)
      - Ledger, 1960 (Box-folder 36/8)
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1915-1966 (Box-folder 36/9)
      - Loan and sale documents, 1919-1926 (Box-folder 36/10)
      - Exhibits regarding case of F. W. Cameron, editor of Labor Advocate, 1910-1920 (Box-folder 36/11)
      - Record of job work, 1936-1941 (Box-folder 36/12)
  - United Labor Advisory Committee of Pierce County, 1956-1962; Records Subgroup 7 (Box-folder 35/6-36/5)
    - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1956-1960; SERIES I (Box-folder 35/6-35/12)
      - Organizational history, 1956 (Box-folder 37/1)
      - Minutes, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 37/2)
      - Minutes: campaign against Initiative 198, 1956 (Box-folder 37/3)
      - Minutes: campaign against Initiative 202, 1958 (Box-folder 37/4)
      - Financial records, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 37/5)
      - Financial records: campaign against Initiative 198, 1956 (Box-folder 37/6)
      - Financial records: campaign against Initiative 202, 1958 (Box-folder 37/7)
    - CORRESPONDENCE AND SUBJECT FILES, 1956-1962; SERIES II (Box-folder 35/13-35/5, 53/3-54/1)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 37/8)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 37/9)
      - Reports, 1956 (Box-folder 37/10)
      - Campaign against Initiative 198: lists, 1956 (Box-folder 37/11)
      - Campaign against Initiative 198: ephemera, 1956 (Box-folder 37/12)
      - Initiative 198: scrapbook, 1956 (Box-folder 53/3)
      - Campaign against Initiative 202: campaign materials, 1958 (Box-folder 37/13)
      - Campaign against Initiative 202: newsletters, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 37/14)
      - Campaign against Initiative 202: clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 37/15)
      - Newsletters and campaign materials, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 37/16)
      - Campaign against Initiative 202: ephemera, 1958 (Box-folder 37/17)
      - Initiative 202: scrapbook, 1958 (Box-folder 54/1)
  - Washington Vocational Training Board. Apprentice Training Council, 1933-1946; Records Subgroup 8 (Box-folder 36/6-36/15)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 38/1)
    - Minutes: Washington State Apprenticeship Council, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Minutes: other organizations, 1936 (Box-folder 38/3)
    - Court documents, Undated (Box-folder 38/4)
    - Reports, 1935 (Box-folder 38/5)
    - Legislation, 1933-1937 (Box-folder 38/6)
    - Bulletins, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 38/7)
    - Newsletter: Apprenticeship Information, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 38/8)
    - Establishment of apprenticeship training programs, 1934-1945 (Box-folder 38/9)
    - Apprenticeship graduation exercises: program, 1942 (Box-folder 38/10)
  - Tacoma Women's Union Card and Label League, 1915-1925; Records Subgroup 9 (Box-folder 37/1-37/2)
    - Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 38/11)
    - Minutes, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 38/12)
- Pierce County Central Labor Council interview, 1978-1979; 2882-002; .06 cubic feet of textual materials plus 1 sound cassette (75 min.)
  Tape recorded interview of Harry S. McIlvaigh conducted by Clyde Hupp on 30 Oct 1978; recollection by Clyde Hupp on 3 Jan 1979.
  On side A, McIlvaigh discusses the acquisition and sites of the labor temple in Tacoma, apprenticeship programs, and the 1935 Lumber and Sawmill Workers strike in Tacoma. On side B, Hupp reflects about the original labor temple in Tacoma at 15th & Market, the Labor Center at 750 Fawcett (occupied in 1972) and its sale in 1979. He reflects on the circumstances which led to the Council's move from this latter building. Harry McIlvaigh was a railroad machinist and secretary-treasurer of the Pierce County Central Labor Council, 1933-1963.
  Listen to the audio recording and view the transcript of this interview on the Libraries Digital Collections site.
  Open to serious research (some background knowledge required) by most researchers including undergraduate students and Council officers. Others admitted only by telephone referrral of the Council Secretary-Treasurer or President.
  Donated by the Council, 5/28/1982.
- Pierce County Central Labor Council meeting minutes, 1890-1926; 2882-003; .28 cubic feet (3 microfilm reels, negative)
  Microfilmed minutes April 1890-June 1919 and Executive Board minutes 1915, 1918-March 1926.
  Open to all users.
- Pierce County Central Labor Council records, 1942-1989; 1947-1986; 2882-004; 15 cubic feet (15 boxes)
  Minutes, 1947-1974; correspondence, reports, financial records, newsletters, subject series, committee files.
  Donated by the Council, 3/18/1993.
  - Series I: Minutes, 1947-1980 (Box-folder 1/1-2/3; 13/13)
    - Minutes Board of Directors Labor Temple Corporation, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Minutes Board of Directors Labor Temple Corporation, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Minutes Board of Directors Labor Temple Corporation, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Minutes Pierce County Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Minutes Pierce County Committee On Political Education (C.O.P.E.), AFL-CIO and Executive Board and Trustees of C.O.P.E., 1958-1974 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Minutes Pierce County Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Minutes Pierce County Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Labor Studies Advisory Council: Meeting Agendas, Minutes, Resolutions, Course Outlines and Descriptions, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Series II: Correspondence, 1947-1989 (Box-folder 3/1-3/39; 4/1-4/34; 6/9-6/30; 7/1-7/18; 7/20-7/23; 8/1-8/21; 9/1; 10/13-10/23; 11/1-11/11; 12/1-12/7; 13/12; 13/14-13/16; 13/18-13/28; 14/1-14/4)
    - Subseries A: Outgoing Correspondence, 1947-1974 (Box-folder 3/1-3/7; 4/1-4/3)
      - Outgoing Correspondence (1 of 7), 1947-1973 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Outgoing Correspondence (2 of 7), 1947-1973 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Outgoing Correspondence (3 of 7), 1947-1973 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Outgoing Correspondence (4 of 7), 1947-1973 (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Outgoing Correspondence (5 of 7), 1947-1973 (Box-folder 3/5)